So far, you already have one algorithm for temporal difference control.
到目前为止 已经有了一个时间差分控制算法
Remember that in the Sarsa algorithm,
注意 对于 Sarsa 算法
we begin by initializing all action values to
我们先将所有动作值初始化为 0
zero in constructing the corresponding Epsilon Greedy policy.
并构建相应的 Epsilon 贪婪策略
Then, the agent begins interacting with the environment and receives the first state.
然后 智能体开始与环境互动并接收第一个状态
Next, it uses the policy to choose it's action.
接着 它使用该策略选择动作
Immediately after it, it receives a reward and next state.
紧接着 它收到一个奖励和下个状态
Then, the agent again uses the same policy to pick the next action.
然后 智能体再次使用相同的策略选择下个动作
After choosing that action,
选择该动作后
it updates the action value corresponding to the previous state action pair,
它会更新对应于上个状态动作对的动作值
and improves the policy to be Epsilon Greedy with
并根据最新的动作估值
respect to the most recent estimate of the action values.
将该策略更新为 Epsilon 贪婪策略
For the remainder of this video,
在本视频的后续阶段
we'll build off this algorithm to design
我们将根据该算法
another control algorithm that works slightly differently.
设计另一个稍微有所不同的控制算法
This algorithm is called Sarsamax,
该算法叫做 Sarsamax
but it's also known as Q-Learning.
亦称之为 Q 学习
We'll still begin with the same initial values for the action values and the policy.
我们依然采用相同的初始动作值和策略
The agent receives the initial state,
智能体接收初始状态
the first action is still chosen from the initial policy.
依然根据初始策略选择第一个动作
But then, after receiving the reward and next state,
但是在接收奖励和下个状态后
we're going to do something else.
我们将执行不同的操作
Namely, we'll update the policy before choosing the next action.
即我们将在选择下个动作之前更新策略
And can you guess what action makes sense to put here?
你能猜到这里适合采用什么样的动作吗？
Well, in the Sarsa case,
对于 Sarsa 算法
our update step was one step later and plugged in
我们的更新步骤是晚一个步骤
the action that was selected using the Epsilon Greedy policy.
并代入使用 Epsilon 贪婪策略选择的动作
And for every step of the algorithm,
对于该算法的每一步
it was the case that all of the actions we used for updating the action values,
我们更新动作值使用的所有动作
exactly coincide with those that were experienced by the agent.
都完全与智能体体验的动作一样
But in general, this does not have to be the case.
但是通常并非必须这样
In particular, consider using the action from the Greedy policy,
尤其是 考虑使用贪婪策略的动作
instead of the Epsilon Greedy policy.
而不是使用 Epsilon 贪婪策略的动作
This is in fact what Sarsamax or Q-Learning does.
这就是 Sarsamax 或 Q 学习的流程
And in this case, you can rewrite the equation to look
在这种情况下 你可以重写该方程
like this where we rely on the fact that
相当于某个状态
the greedy action corresponding to a state is
对应的贪婪动作
just the one that maximizes the action values for that state.
正好是最大化该状态的动作值的动作
And so what happens is after we update
发生的情况是当我们使用贪婪动作
the action value for time step zero using the greedy action,
更新时间步 0 的动作值后
we then select A1 using
我们使用刚刚更新的动作值
the Epsilon greedy policy corresponding to the action values we just updated.
对应的 Epsilon 贪婪策略选择 A1
And this continues when we received a reward and next state.
当我们收到奖励和下个状态后继续这一流程
Then, we do the same thing we did before where we update the value
然后像之前使用贪婪动作
corresponding to S1 and A1 using the greedy action,
更新 S1 和 A1 对应的动作一样
then we select A2 using the corresponding Epsilon greedy policy.
使用相应的 Epsilon 贪婪策略选择 A2
To understand precisely what this update stuff is doing,
为了清晰地理解这个更新步骤的作用
we'll compare it to the corresponding step in the Sarsa algorithm.
我们将其与 Sarsa 算法中的相应步骤进行比较
And in Sarsa, the update step pushes the action values closer to
在 Sarsa 中 更新步骤使动作值更接近于
evaluating whatever Epsilon greedy policy is currently being followed by the agent.
智能体当前遵守 Epsilon 贪婪策略获得的动作值
And it's possible to show that Sarsamax instead,
可以显示 Sarsamax
directly attempts to approximate the optimal value function at every time step.
直接在每个时间步估算最优值函数
Soon, you'll have the chance to implement this yourself and
很快你将有机会自己实现此步骤
directly examine the difference between these two algorithms.
并直接研究这两个算法之间的区别